# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I'm going to share with you a homestyle dish
# 姜葱焗鲈鱼
Baked Sea Bass with Ginger and Onion
# 首先我们准备鲈鱼1条（约750克）
First, prepare a bass fish (~750 grams)
# 将鱼敲晕之后刮去鱼鳞去除内脏清洗干净备用
Stun it, remove scales and guts, and rinse it clean
# 下一步开始改刀
Next, cut the fish
# 首先我们从鱼肚下刀
Cut from the belly first
# 将两边的鱼肉切开露出脊骨
Cut the fish open to expose the spine
# 然后切掉尾部多余的脊骨
Then cut out the spine near its tail
# 切掉尾骨之后在鲈鱼的两边各切上一字花刀
After removing the tail, score both sides of the fish
# 这一步的目的是方便成菜入味和成熟
This step is for better flavor penetration and faster cooking
# 下一步开始准备酱料
Next, prepare the sauce
# 碗中加入蚝油20克
Add 20 grams of oyster sauce
# 加入排骨酱和海鲜酱各30克
Add 30 grams of spare rib sauce and 30 grams of hoisin sauce
# 加入食用盐1勺（约2克）
Add a spoon of salt (~2 grams)
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add some pepper powder
# 最后加入香辣豆豉90克搅拌均匀备用
Finally, add 90 grams of spicy "Douchi" (fermented soybeans) and stir it well
# 然后将调好的酱料均匀地涂抹在鲈鱼两边腌制30分钟
Brush the sauce evenly on both sides of the fish and marinate for 30 minutes
# 同学们香辣豆豉可以参考往期的教学
Please refer to the previous video on how to make spicy "Douchi" (fermented soybeans)
# 下一步开始准备料头
Next, prepare the other ingredients
# 准备洋葱1个对半切开之后切成小片备用（约200克）
Cut an onion into halves, and cut it into small pieces (~200 grams)
# 准备生姜2块切成姜片备用（约40克）
Cut 2 pieces of ginger into slices (~40 grams)
# 准备大蒜几颗切成小粒备用（约30克）
Cut some garlic into small dices (~30 grams)
# 然后在砂锅中加入食用盐1勺搅拌均匀
Add one spoon of salt into the claypot and mix well
# 加盐搅拌的目的是让料头出水防止烧糊
The purpose of this step is to draw the moisture out of the ingredients and prevent burning
# 最后再把腌制好的鲈鱼放入砂锅中下一步开始制作
Finally, put the marinated fish into the claypot and start cooking
# 首先我们把砂锅放在灶上开大火烧开
First, place the claypot on a burner and bring to a boil over high heat
# 大火烧开之后继续盖上盖子转小火烧10分钟即可
Once boiled, cover with lid and cook over low heat for 10 minutes
# 10分钟之后用筷子插入鱼身
10 minutes later, poke the fish with a chopstick
# 如果很容易插透即说明鲈鱼已熟
If it pokes through easily, the fish is well cooked
# 最后撒上葱花即可上菜
Finally, sprinkle some chopped spring onion, and the dish is done!
# 一道非常美味的姜葱焗鲈鱼就制作完成
A very delicious Baked Sea Bass with Ginger and Onion is ready to serve!
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，原材料最好选择少刺或者无刺的鱼
# 第二，垫底的料头姜葱可以适当的多加一些
# 第三，不能吃辣的同学可以根据个人口味调制酱料
# 第四，制作的前部分必须开大火烧开然后再转小火烧
# 姜葱焗鲈鱼的技术总结完毕
Next, technical summary
First, it's better to choose fish with few or no bones
Second, it's OK to use more ginger and onion as the base
Third, if you don't like spicy food, you can make your own sauce that you like
Fourth, you should use high heat first until boiling and then turn to low heat
That's the end of the technical summary